Dan Stuart

Co-Founder Bidvine (Techstars London), ex-LivingSocial, GoNabit

dan_stuart@hotmail.com

Summary

I currently lead product and design as a co-founder of Bidvine - a Techstars London Winter 2014 cohort participant. I'm based between London, UK and Guelph, Canada. My expertise lies in conceptualising and leading product development plus developing, stress-testing and operationalising business models for online marketplaces. Plus, I'm great at identifying talent. My chief professional success was founding and leading GoNabit as CEO. GoNabit was the first and leading group-buying site in the MENA region. I led the expansion of GoNabit from the UAE to Lebanon, Kuwait, Jordan and Egypt. GoNabit was acquired by LivingSocial in July 2011 in the Middle East's first e-commerce acquisition. Post-acquisition I held senior positions at LivingSocial including Managing Director (CEO) MENA and Senior Director Canada. I have also held senior roles in ad tech at AdGear where I led sales and go-to-market strategy and at Bayt.com as Chief Possibility Officer. At Bayt I owned business development, corporate strategy and new product initiatives. Furthermore, I held an intrapreneur role convening internal teams to launch new businesses. I also founded Intilaq - Bayt's corporate venture capital arm - looking at seed funding for early stage ventures. My 4 years at Bayt.com began as Sales Director of the Enterprise Sales Division where I built the Enterprise Sales team from cold-start to 30 staff in 9 cities across 6 countries in the Middle East. Recently I have become an active advisor, mentor and angel investor providing capital and time to early-stage technology startups and young entrepreneurs. I have a Masters Degree in Education from the University of Toronto, and a Hons. BA from Wilfrid Laurier University.

Experience

Mentor at Flat6Labs

December 2014 - Present (6 months)

Co Founder at Bidvine

August 2014 - Present (10 months)

Member of the Techstars London Winter 2014 cohort. Commercial team in London, UK and Development team in Waterloo, CA. Amongst other things, I manage product & design.

Mentor at Futurpreneur Canada

June 2014 - Present (1 year)

Mentor: - satorifoster.com - happenate.com

Advisor at FlashProps, Inc.

September 2013 - Present (1 year 9 months)

FlashProps is a stealth Mobile-Social technology start-up.

Vice President Business Development at AdGear

October 2013 - August 2014 (11 months)

Lead and execute all sales, positioning and go-to-market strategy.

Senior Director, Canada at LivingSocial

October 2012 - June 2013 (9 months)

Relocated to Canada to a new role as Senior Director, Canada. Full responsibility for planning and executing countrywide sales strategy, developing growth levers, and growing a competitive market position. Own the country-level net revenue goal, with straight-line management of the outside sales team including a sales director and two sales managers. Report to Senior VP of Sales.

CEO, Middle East at LivingSocial

June 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Migrated to LivingSocial after the sale of GoNabit to LivingSocial in June 2011. Full responsibility for P&L, marketing, BD, FP&A, sales and operations for the Middle East. Managed a team of 95 and reported to President of International.

CEO & Co Founder at GoNabit

February 2010 - October 2011 (1 year 9 months)

Founded and served as CEO of GoNabit.com. Self-funded through launch in May 2010, seed round in June 2010, and exit to LivingSocial in June 2011. Launched GoNabit in UAE, Lebanon, Kuwait, Jordan and Egypt. Setting the vision while also being/leading product management, BD, marketing, HR, and finance.

Founder & Managing Director, Intilag at Bayt.com

April 2009 - February 2010 (11 months)

Launched and served as Director of Intilaq. Intilaq (Arabic word for "launch") was Bayt.com's corporate venture capital arm to fund and support aspiring entrepreneur technologists in early-stage technology startups.

Chief Possibility Officer at Bayt.com

May 2008 - February 2010 (1 year 10 months)

Special projects, product management, C-level BD role plus internal entrepreneur working with cross-functional teams to conceptualize, plan, implement and grow new business ideas outside Bayt.com's existing online and revenue footprint. Founder and Director of Intilaq – Bayt.com's corporate venture capital arm. Reported to the CEO.

Sales Director - Enterprise Division at Bayt.com

August 2006 - May 2008 (1 year 10 months)

Founding member of the Enterprise sales team. Tasked with individual selling and building the team throughout the Middle East. Assumed responsibility for developing and executing the Enterprise business plan, staff and comp planning, hiring and training. Led 23 sales and 9 support staff. Reported to COO.

Education

Villanova University

Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, 2008 - 2008

University of Toronto - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education

M.Ed, Curriculum, Theory and Learning, 2004 - 2006

D'Youville College

B.Ed, Education, 2001 - 2002

Wilfrid Laurier University

Hons. BA, English Literature, History, 1992 - 1996

Activities and Societies: Football team; VP, Letterman's Club

Skills & Expertise

Start-ups

Entrepreneurship

Strategy

Business Development

E-commerce

Product Management

Online Advertising

Marketing Strategy

Product Development

Digital Marketing

Cross-functional Team Leadership

Social Media Marketing

Digital Strategy

Business Planning

Leadership

User Interface Design

Marketing

Management

User Experience Design

Strategic Partnerships

Sales

Public Speaking

Business Strategy

Strategic Planning

CRM

Partnerships

Online Marketing Sales Management Venture Capital Lead Generation Social Media Digital Media

SEO

Start-up Consulting

Marketing Communications

Fundraising

Advertising

Training

Competitive Analysis

Recruiting

Mentoring

Cross Functional Team Building Multi-cultural team building

HTML

CSS

User Experience Testing

Design

Publications

Alberta Journal of Educational Research

Alberta, CA February 2008

Authors: Dan Stuart, Mitzi G. Mitchell, Hilary Montgomery, Michelle Holder

The cooperative learning strategy of group investigation has been used extensively in elementary and high school classrooms. Whereas this learning strategy seems to benefit low- and middle-achieving students, the performance of high-achieving students seems to change little. This article examines the literature on group investigation as a cooperative learning strategy and offers suggestions for areas of future investigation and research.

Interests

Triathlon, snowboarding, reading, skiing, design.

Dan Stuart

Co-Founder Bidvine (Techstars London), ex-LivingSocial, GoNabit

dan_stuart@hotmail.com



Contact Dan on LinkedIn